M.S. Brooks Company Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
M.S. Brooks Company Records.
1864-1944.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
M.S. Brooks Company.
2 linear feet.
MSS20000081
History
In 1848 Simeon Brooks of Chester, Connecticut, began the manufacture of wood screw eyes and screws. Merritt Brooks, Simeon's son, developed the first machine to bend screw eyes automatically. The business prospered and in 1857 the Brooks' built a factory in Chester. After Simeon's death in 1864, Merritt continued the business until 1874, when he leased the factory to his brother-in-law William N. Clark. Merritt again assumed control of the business in February 1886 and soon his sons, Hilton C. and Simeon S., joined the business. Hilton Brooks acquired sole interest in the business in 1916. When Hilton's sons, Louis M. and Malcolm G., came into the business it was incorporated as M.S. Brooks & Sons. Hilton died in 1934, leaving his two sons in charge.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of twelve volumes of financial ledgers and accounts as well as some product illustrations.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of business financial records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Financial Records.
Occupations:
Manufacturer.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Donated to Archives & Special Collections by Mrs. Helen Brooks in 2000 via the Chester Historical Society.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Records, 1864-1944
  - Customer accounts, 1864 April - 1866 (Volume 1)
  - Customer accounts, 1864 April - 1873 (Volume 2)
  - Customer accounts, 1867 January - 1871 (Volume 3)
  - Customer accounts, 1886 February - 1888, August (Volume 4)
  - Customer accounts, 1886 February - 1891 (Volume 5)
  - Cash accounts, 1886 February - 1894 August (Volume 6)
  - Cash accounts, 1894 September - 1901 September (Volume 7)
  - Customer order book, 1895 (Volume 8)
  - Customer accounts, 1911 October - 1912 June (Volume 9)
  - Scale drawings of products sold by company (in ledger book), 1908 (Volume 10)
  - Customer accounts, 1917 December - 1918 November (Volume 11)
  - Customer accounts, 1939 August - 1944 (Volume 12)
  - Customer order book, 1885 (Folder Folder 1)
  - Two completed order forms, 1886 (Folder Folder 2)
  - Papers, including price lists, specifications for products, book-keeper's oath, members oath, advertisements for equipment, and drawings of products. (Folder Folder 3)